Jan Sedlacek

Permanently residing: Czech Republic – Prague

sedlacek.off@gmail.com
+420 733 161 362



OVERVIEW

I specialize in the cyber security field, with a self-perfecting in development of dockerized apps with a current focus on web services, offensive and defensive security via platforms such as Try Hack Me, Attack Defense and LetsDefend. I have rich experience of international culture and face international discussions on a daily basis. I am used to taking the assignment collected and agreed with contractor, defining important milestones and relating and reviewing the project until it completion with final presentation to the contractor.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cybersecurity Engineer

T-Mobile Cross border services / B2B

2019 – present

Cooperation across multiple NATcos in agile principles on topics including implementation of SOAR platform (as System architect) deployed of 4+ countries interconnecting and standardizing the SOC processes, introducing potential automization to the incident investigation and content development utilizing arbitrary 3rd party services. Participating in customer discussions for technical sessions and customizing the content based on customer feedback. Vulnerability management of Web applications and IP components (utilizing Qualys and Nessus). Full stack development of PKI automization (Python, Flask framework and PostgreSQL). Migration and Upgrade of inhouse reporting tool (Python, Django, Angular). Penetration testing of medium size company's network and voice services, including custom testing tool development interacting with hardware (Qualys, Nessus, nmap, msfconsol, Python, Raspbery).

- SOAR deployment SOC automation
- Cooperation with pentester team
- Voicemail penetration testing
- Automatization of certificate issuing
- Vulnerability management

Developer and IT security specialist

Westudents

2019 (6 months)

Development of a Web-base software (Java) for processing and editing of video streams. Implementing parallelization to the product. Developing and creating user interface for backed processes. Management of user data processing from application via Google contacts and developing custom API interactions. Preparation of details for Asset management/inventory, active scanning of network and app components for vulnerabilities.

- Software development video editing
- Security testing of webserver

Developer and Team coordinator

Tongji university software institute 2017 – 2018

Development of an Andriod application (using Java) for image processing, collecting the expected requirements. Leading team discussions, assigning tasks, and developing the core backend, presenting the resulting product to the public audience.

• Software development – Android application

Assistant of technical support

2016

Cooperating with a technical supervisor on identification, analysis, and resolution of IT-related problems in small networks with several tens of machines.

- Analysis of Network and PC issues
- · Basic server and PC maintenance

Remedial educator

2016 - 2018

Teaching Elementary and high school topics (mainly online), focused on practical explenations/Showcases of the topics.

- Math
- Physics
- Chemistry

Laboratory Assistant

ÚHKT (Prague, Czech)

2016

- Preparations of substances for sample analysis
- Extractions of DNA from samples
- Evaluations of analysis results

Junior Developer

Waldorfske lyceum

2015

- Developing of text game environment
- Bug finding in a text game

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Czech Technical University

2019 - 2021

- Engineering degree
- Computer security
- · Improving sessions for international students
- Study language: English
- Master Thesis: Analyzes and Design of Bug Bounty platforms

Tongji University

2017 - 2018

- Part of Bachelor degree
- Chinese/European culture exchange
- High-level circuit design
- Study language: English

Politecnico di Torino

2016 - 2019

- Bachelor degree
- Computer Engineering
- Part of Tongji Project
- Study language: English
- Bachelor Thesis: Analyzes and Implementation of Video processing WebApp and basic security assessment of network

High school

2012 - 2016

- Scientific specializations
- Ecological stage and cultural exchange Romania
- Artistic conference Netherlands
- Geometer stage Czech Republic
- Woodcrafting Czech Republic
- Supervision of handicapped children Czech Republic

LANGUAGES

Czech – Native speaker English – C1 certified German – Basics

CERTIFICATIONS

IELTS - C1

since 2018

Wi-Fi Penetration testing

since 2018

B1 driving licence

since 2015

SKILLS

Good Knowledge:

- Python (Web Sockets, Multithreading, Flask, OOP)
- SOAR
- Networking
- Linux system (Ubuntu/Debian based)
- Containers (Docker/Podman)
- Vulnerability Management (Qualys/Nessus)

Average Knowledge:

- Bash
- GIT (Gitlab, Github)
- Jira
- Penetration Testing (nmap, msfconsole, nikto, gobuster, ..)
- Threat Intel

Basic Knowledge:

- C/C++
- Reverse engineering/ Assemby (Ida, OllyDbg, dotPeek)
- Java
- VMware

INTERESTS

Self-education

IT security field and software trends, with current focus on dockerized app development in python, deepening my knowhow in penetration testing and relevant tools. Improving my knowledge of Blue team security including SOC activities, binary reverse engineering, and memory forensics.

Sport and collective activities Travelling and countryside trails Reading Fantasy/Sci-fi books